# Matt Pityo

Tampa, Fl • 727-421-9122 • mpityo@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/matt-pityo • Portfolio: mpityo.github.io/matt-pityo-portfolio/ •

GitHub: github.com/mpityo

### **Summary**

I am a full stack developer that has spent 10 years in the customer service field, running a business that has over 1M OCF and a 4.8 average star rating. However, programming has always been a passion and goal, with merging creative ideas with a technical know how. Utilizing Javascript to its full power with Node, Express, and React will lead to creating and supporting your products.

#### **Technical Skills**

**Technical**: Node • Express • React • Sequelize/MySQL • MongoDB • PWA • Object Oriented

Programming

**Languages**: Javascript • HTML 5/CSS • Java

Professional: Works well under pressure • Communication • Teamwork • Organization

# **Projects**

#### **Tech Blog** | github.com/mpityo/tech-blog | tech-blog-211.herokuapp.com

SQL • Sequelize • Node • Express • bcrypt • CSS • HTML5

A *full*-stack application designed to allow users to talk about tech related news and products. Features a SQL database, backend routing for comments, likes, posts, and a sleek and ituative front end design. Also utilizes encryption for user passwords, and environmental values for secure access.

Role: Sole author

#### Social Network Backend | github.com/mpityo/social-network-backend

MongoDB • Mongoose • Node • Express

A back end application showcasing my ability to work with new softwares (MongoDB) to create a fully functional back end for a social network website. Incorporates DRY and RESTful APIs to route and manage actions including creating, deleting, updating, and getting (CRUD).

Role: Sole author

#### Food Festival | github.com/mpityo/food-festival | mpityo.github.io/food-festival

PWA • Webpacks • IndexedDB • Node • HTML5 • Bootstrap (CSS) • Lighthouse

A front end PWA application that allows users to access information about a food festival, while having low to no internet connection. Fully PWA with a downloadable application,

offline saving and uploading via IndexedDB and service workers, and optimized loading of JS and images.

Role: Back end developer

## **Experience**

#### Pearson Vue - Tampa, FL

Mar 2021 - Present

Test Administrator, Part Time

- Admit and proctor 75 candidates per day, following strict guidelines from over 30 test sponsors, in a high stakes environment.
- Retain an intense attention to detail to ensure candidates have required documents, identification, and do not bring any prohibited materials into the testing room.
- Implement cleaning procedures for computers and other high use items in the office. Come up with a way to track/monitor the completion of these items and share results with the team on a monthly basis.
- Within 3 months of starting the position, train new test administrators and work at other offices to assist with coverage.

#### AMC Entertainment - Tampa, FL

Sep 2011 - Jul 2020

General Manager - Senior Manager - Supervisor - Film Crew

- Implement 30+ projects that support customer growth and engagement. These led to a 34% increase in yearly attendance (up to 1.1M from 700k in 3 years).
- Create a new training program for Crew Leads to train new hires more efficiently, as well as a quarterly review process for the management team to assess the Crew Leads. This ensured the up and coming leaders were placed in the best position for promotion.
- Hire, train, support, and lead a group of 6 operation managers.
- Work independently to find and solve problems before they arise. Leverage management team to find solutions and implement within a reasonable time frame.
- Compose and send emails and communications daily to fellow leaders, crew, escalated guest correspondence, and corporate partners.

# **Education**

UCF Boot Camp	Dec 2021 - Jun 2022
	200 -0-1 0411 -0

Certificate - Full Stack Web Development

Hillsborough Community College - Tampa, FL

Associate of Arts – 3.75 GPA Aug 2020 - Dec 2021

University of Florida - Gainesville, FL

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science Expected Dec 2023